novamind.com 2015-04-06

# NovaMind Privacy Policy - NovaMind.com

NovaMind has established this Privacy Policy to explain how it protects and manages the personal information that it collects from you (the customer) online. 

* #### Consent for Collection, Use and Disclosure

Your use of the NovaMind site and/or your registration for NovaMind products and services constitute your consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the NovaMind site. 

NovaMind may occasionally update this Privacy Policy and will post the changes at this or another specified location. 

A customer may withdraw his or her consent for collection, use and disclosure at any time. Please note that, if you do, NovaMind may suspend its provision of products and services to you. 

* #### Accountability 

NovaMind collects, at the time of your registration and your sign-on to its web site, certain “personal information” (information that personally identifies you) which may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, home or work address, telephone number, and information about your computer hardware and software (e.g., IP address, operating system, browser type, domain name, URL, access times, and referring web site addresses). 

NovaMind has implemented this Privacy Policy to protect personal information received from its customers, and to respond to any inquiries. The Privacy Policy also provides that NovaMind will use appropriate means to establish a comparable level of protection for personal information which is sent for processing by third parties on NovaMind’s behalf. 

* #### Purposes for Collecting Personal Information 

NovaMind collects and uses personal information for the following Identified Purposes: 

  1. #### to understand customer needs regarding NovaMind’s services;

  2. #### to develop and provide our web site and our products and services for our customers;

  3. #### to fulfill your requests for products, services or information;

  4. #### to communicate with customers and site visitors, when necessary, and to inform customers of upgrades, as well as of other products and services available from NovaMind, its affiliates and third parties; 

  5. #### to allow customers to access limited-entry areas of NovaMind’s site;

  6. #### to personalize some of our services and products for you and to deliver targeted advertisements and offers from NovaMind and third parties; 

  7. #### to bill accounts and maintain payment records; 

  8. #### to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or government request;

  9. #### to respond to a legitimate claim, or to address our reasonable belief, that you are violating the rights of any third party or any of the agreements or policies that govern your use of the NovaMind site or any NovaMind product or service;

  10. #### to protect the services, products or rights of NovaMind, including but not limited to the security or integrity of the NovaMind site; and

  11. #### to identify and resolve technical problems concerning NovaMind’s site, products and services.

If we hire other companies to provide some products or services on our behalf, then we will only provide those companies the personal information they need for the Identified Purposes, and we will limit their rights to use and further disclose your personal information as appropriate in the course of their work for us. 

* #### Limiting the Collection of Personal Information 

NovaMind limits its collection of personal information to only that information which is necessary for the Identified Purposes.¬? NovaMind does not direct its site to, nor does it knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen. 

When you visit the NovaMind web site, a cookie may be placed on your computer or the cookie may be read if you have visited the NovaMind site previously.¬? NovaMind uses cookies to allow NovaMind to determine which products and services you have already purchased so that NovaMind does not provide redundant information to you, and, if you are an NovaMind affiliate, to track NovaMind sales made to customers referred by you so that you can receive compensation under our affiliate program.¬? If you choose to not have your browser accept cookies from the NovaMind web site, you may not be able to view all the text on the screens, or to experience a personalised visit, or to subscribe to certain service and product offerings on the NovaMind site. 

* #### Disclosure, Processing and Retention 

NovaMind does not sell, rent or disclose your personal information to anyone else, except: 

  1. ####  to someone you have designated to act as your agent, for one or more of the Identified Purposes (listed in Section 2, above);

  2. ####  a very limited amount, and in very few cases, to NovaMind’s employees, independent contractors, subsidiaries, affiliates, consultants, business associates, service providers, suppliers and agents, acting on NovaMind’s behalf for any of the Identified Purposes;

  3. ####  as necessary if NovaMind has reason to believe that disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference (either intentionally or unintentionally) with NovaMind’s rights or property, other users of NovaMind’s web site, products or services, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities; and

  4. ####  to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law. 

In addition, as we continue to develop our business, we or our affiliates may sell or buy other businesses or entities, or we may merge with another company. In such transactions, personal information may be one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that NovaMind or substantially all of its assets are acquired, your personal information may be one of the transferred assets. 

Your information may be stored and processed in Australia, the Netherlands, Germany, the United States, or in any other country in which NovaMind or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities.¬? By using this web site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. 

After your account becomes inactive (that is, if you request to be removed from our database), NovaMind will keep your personal information in its archives. Your information will then be used only as necessary for tax reasons or to prove NovaMind’s compliance with any applicable law. 

* #### Accuracy of Personal Information 

NovaMind will use reasonable efforts to keep customer personal information accurate for the Identified Purposes, and for minimizing the possibility of making inappropriate customer decisions based on such information.¬? Customers are responsible for informing NovaMind about changes to their personal information.¬?NovaMind will use new or updated personal information it receives from customers to update its own records. 

* #### Security Safeguards 

NovaMind will use reasonable efforts to protect customers’ personal information. 

* #### Access to Personal Information 

NovaMind will afford you a reasonable opportunity to review the personal information in your file, if you so request by writing to: 

NovaMind Software 

3/61 Commercial Dr 

Shailer Park 

QLD 4128 

Australia 

If NovaMind is not able to provide access to some aspect of a customer’s personal information, it will provide reasons for denying access such as; that by doing so would likely reveal personal information about a third party, or that it is confidential commercial information or attorney-client privileged communications, or that the information relates to a breach of an agreement or a contravention of law, or that its disclosure could reasonably be expected to threaten the life or security of another individual. 

Customers have the right to request that inaccurate or incomplete information be amended as appropriate, by contacting NovaMind as described above. NovaMind will promptly correct such personal information.
